Danger, intrigue, romance...and a touch of kinkiness!
High Anxiety is a comedy, mystery, thriller film directed by Mel Brooks.
A psychiatrist with intense acrophobia (fear of heights) goes to work for a mental institution run by doctors who
appear to be crazier than their patients, and have secrets that they are willing to commit murder to keep.
Dr. Richard H. Thorndyke, played by Mel Brooks.
Victoria Brisbane, played by Madeline Kahn.
Nurse Charlotte Diesel, played by Cloris Leachman.
Dr. Charles Montague, played by Harvey Korman.
Brophy, played by Ron Carey.
Professor Lilloman, played by Howard Morris.
High Anxiety is a 1977 American satirical comedy mystery film produced
and directed by Mel Brooks, who also plays the lead.
This is Brooks' first film as a producer and first speaking lead
role (his first lead role was in Silent Movie).
Veteran Brooks ensemble members Madeline Kahn, Cloris
Leachman, and Harvey Korman are also featured.
It is a parody of psychoanalysis and Alfred Hitchcock films.
The film explores themes of hitman, vertigo, lighthouse, satire, industrialist.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending and intense.